Heat. Heat. N.
[music]
>> [music]
>> How we doing?
>> Good. Um
been a lot that's uh transpired here um
really since the uh end of the season.
Um you know we're still in the process
of kind of looking at everything the
cutups offense, defense, special teams.
Um defense is really what we've been
involved in. I've been involved in with
Shep and those guys because we have the
staff intact. Uh fortunate to be able to
keep Jim O'Neal. uh you know, he had an
opportunity to go with the Jets, so that
worked out good for us. Um so really we
got the staff still intact and it's
about cleaning up some of those little
things. Um and then offensively it's uh
Drew kind of getting up to speed with
our terminology. Uh he's been getting
together with golf and uh you know and
and just trying to make sure that we get
everything that that kind of makes sense
for for him but us for us as well and he
and golf. and then we'll start hitting
the cutups. So, that's kind of where
we're at with that. Um, you know, Drew
was fortunate to find him. I've always
liked Drew, uh, from afar, you know,
facing those guys. Uh, but then just
watching, uh, common opponents,
um, you know, through the years, what he
was able to do offensively,
uh, I just I always liked it. You know,
there was creativity to it. Uh, you
know, certainly they've used a lot of
heavy sets lately. Uh but that's where
that's where their roster has gone. You
know, that's not that's not something
that um that I I foresee us being. We
just we're going to be versatile, but he
gives us that ability to to make the
most of what we have. Um and I just
think he understands the protections. I
understands the run game. He understands
the pass game, certainly quarterback
play. So, I think he's got it all. He's
coached receivers, coached uh tight
ends, coach quarterbacks, and I and I
think that's important. It was important
for this one. We had, you know, um, a
lot of different guys to interview. Uh,
it was great. The process was great. A
lot of good men, good coaches, great
coaches really. Um, but he was he was
the right fit. It was, um, I felt that
within 20 minutes. So, um, it was really
good. So, fired up to have him and and
then one of the guys I was really high
on uh, through that whole process was
Mike Kfka, too. And we were fortunate to
get him uh, really pass game
coordinator. So that worked out uh
really well. But a guy who's been our
interim head coach, you know, has
coached quarterbacks, has coached some
good quarterbacks, uh run an offense.
Um so he's got a good, you know, a good
perspective on things. He's got some
pretty good ideas. So um anyway, that
was good. Steve Oliver, we promoted from
assistant old line coach to tight end
coach. He's earned that. Um he's really
been I've interviewed him twice uh over
the last two times we've had that that
position open and it was it was time
he's earned it. So um fired up for him.
Guys are excited.
Um and that's where we're at really.
That's where we're at now. It's just
about how do we improve from here. Brad
and I have have had a number of
conversations.
Free agencies coming on. Um but you know
for me it needed to start with what can
we do a little bit better as coaches. um
we're not that far off. We still had a
top five offense. We just our efficiency
was a little off. So, how do we get a
little bit better uh with what we do as
coaches? And now it's about the roster,
you know, where do we uh where do we
upgrade ourselves? Where do we bring in
some competition? Um
so, excited for another year, man.
>> Yeah.
uh I think that um I mean I think that's
a fair assessment, but I think it more
as you know this is this is my uh so
most time I've had to be able to sit
down with the defense and just go play
by play, cut up by cut up. Um, and well,
let me go back. I think I think Shep,
um, I think Shep did a good job and I
think he learned a lot and I think he
grew a ton. Um, and I love the staff
that's around him. I really do, man. I I
think those guys from from Casey Rogers
to to Shay Townsen to get Jim O'Neal
back, Shawn Dion Hamilton, I just think
it's a really good unit, man. It's an
experienced unit. Um, I think we got a
lot of flexibility on what we do, man.
We just got to tighten the screws on a
few things. Um, but I do I love the
staff and I love what we do, man. Are
there things we've already been through
the cut up like, man, if if if we could
go back, maybe we would play a little
bit more of this or a little less of
this. And so, I think it just there's a
lot of clarity in some things adjusting
when we get a few injuries here and
there. Uh, what can we do better? what
do the players, you know, what can they
do better? Um how complex is this
really? Um is it out of their
wheelhouse? It's just we're asking
somebody to do something they cannot do.
So I think it it's to be able to go into
year two and learn and grow with a guy
who uh is receptive. Uh he's always
looking for answers. He's always looking
for new ways to do things. I'm talking
about Shep and with an experienced staff
around him. Um, so that fired me up and
so that really has been where my focus
has been over the last call it three
weeks.
>> Yeah.
[snorts]
Um
well um your first question to that was
just about uh yeah so I've left him
alone um you know we had a conversation
right when the season ended um you know
about just him taking his time to figure
out this what he really feels like he
wants to do can do and so I I've left
him alone there um I don't want to say
we haven't had a conversation but I'm
leaving that between Yes. Um but you
know, there'll be some um
you know, look, I if it's not, then we
got to find a guy, right? Um but if it
is, we still got to find a guy because
as much as I love Deck, you know, it's u
he's got some things that are that are
going to need some management. Um and
that's kind of where we're at, you know,
and so we're one way or another, we're
going to need somebody that can play
over there. Um you know, and they can
help us if we need them in a crunch or
we need them as a starter. So, that's
important. We've talked about the
interior of the offensive line, too.
That's important. So, um, you know,
we've been digging. We've been looking
at stuff, but until we can kind of
figure a little bit of of those pieces
out, um, and then exactly who is going
to be available, who are we going to
have the ability to potentially go
after? uh how does that affect uh
another position or the depth of the
roster? Then we're kind of we're just
we're waiting it out here a little bit.
>> David is another guy we talked at the
very end of the year. Um, and I told him
I was I was not, you know, I like to
give these guys their space and just let
them uh kind of unwind a little bit in
their own way. Um, they don't need me in
their ear. Um, but certainly, uh, he
knows how I feel. Uh, Drew loves him,
you know. I mean, who who wouldn't? This
guy's, uh, he's a heck of a back, you
know. Um, and so we'll just we'll see
where everything's at, you know. Um,
certainly there's been healthy
conversations, you know. I'm sure Brad
told you guys uh you know probably
mentioned that. So uh all good man.
David's a pro so figure this out.
>> On the community engagement there is an
initiative with the office of Roger's
communications team.
And I'm curious to know if you wouldn't
mind.
>> Give me Yeah. Give me a minute. All
right.
>> That's That's Yeah.
>> Uh that's that's tough to say. You know,
we've been treating him. Um he's he's
done a few things. We're in we're we're
in a um I would say we're in the
position now to where um we're slowly
working him back. You know what is this
going to look like? How is it going to
feel call it a month from now maybe a
month and a half and then we'll I think
we'll have a lot better idea because is
this something where he's going to be
able to handle what it's going to feel
like or is can we get it stable enough?
Can we get enough strength? It's all of
those things.
Well, I I think his uh there's a level
of maturity with him. He did grow, you
know. He uh um he made some plays for us
when we called his number.
Um and and he's tough, man. He he which
is one of the things we loved about him.
You know, we asked him to do some of the
dirty work. He did that. He played teams
for us. I just thought, you know, it's
hard for rookies to really help you and
contribute in their first year. And I
think receiver it's real hard sometimes
uh just because we put so much on those
guys uh from a mental standpoint to have
to do it. And uh I thought man you look
at where he was from game one to the
very last game he he improved and uh
there would be nothing to tell me that
he's not going to take another step this
year. You know I think we're going into
camp a little bit with some confidence
in this guy and that's important as a
rookie. It's important
No, it wasn't that. It It was just the
way that he talked and the way that he
saw the game. Um, man, his his
confidence, his conviction, his
knowledge, uh his detail and everything
and why he was doing what he was doing
and what he was thinking and how he was
uh um and how he was teaching it. Um
throw curves balls at him and he was all
over it. Um I just it was good, man. It
was um I just love the way that I loved
his presence and I love the way that he
taught and I love the detail behind it
and and then I've seen the tape. I know
what the tape is. Um and I just think
he's a creative guy and and can make
things happen with, you know, get tell
me what I got and I'll figure this out.
I love that.
Uh, I think it's very important. You
know, I I do I think you all of those
guys, you're always looking for
something that is maybe a little bit
unique or rare or that somebody has that
one the other guy doesn't. Um, because
now you you can kind of help each other
out and you can lift each other up. Um,
and I do feel like we have that. It was
important to keep the this staff intact.
Um, you know, what we did last year,
what I did last year, look, it didn't
work. It wasn't, it wasn't the perfect
setup. You know, I thought we would be
able to work through those a little bit
better than we did. Didn't work out. All
good. We'll move this way. Um, but I
love the staff that is here in TAC. I
know they'll be able to work with Drew.
Drew will be able to to give those guys
the directive and and they'll respond.
That's what they do, man. Our guys are
doers. They go to work. Um, so I'm fired
up about it.
>> Yeah. So, Mike Clark, I'm glad you
brought that up. Director of US strength
performance,
um, is retiring. Uh, somebody I've known
a long time, been in this profession for
50 years. Um, and, you know, he's I
mean, he's one of these, you know, you
go inside those circles, he's a legend.
And, uh, I've lived it firsthand. The
guy's been unbelievable. Um, I I've
loved the program, everything that he's
brought to the table. Um, so we're going
to miss him, you know, we're going to
miss him. Um, but he felt like it was
time and um, and you know, Josh Schuler
will be head strength coach and he'll be
running that area. Um, taking care of
business over there. He's earned that as
well. You know, he's learned from Mike.
So, uh, we're excited moving forward.
>> Yeah. Well, Deck, you know, here's what
I'll say about Declan. Even from the
time when I was with him in New Orleans,
there was somebody made a comment about
how young he seems, right? And he is
young, but even back then, I mean, think
about this. This was golly, 18, 19, I
don't know what that was now. Um, you
know, but you're talking about another
seven years. He was seven years younger.
He was a young, you would never know it.
the way that he uh the questions that he
asked, the way that he taught, the
information he gave to the players or
ideas that he had, he was man
had a lot of conviction. Um man,
understands football, asks the right
questions. Um he's always trying to
solve problems. Um and when he coaches
his you see him, he comes alive. You
know, before that he's a little he's a
little low-key. heat, but man, the
minute the football is laid out, you see
his passion. So, I'm not surprised one
bit. Um, not surprised that Ben hired
him. He did a great job and now he's
where he's at. So, I I think this guy's
going to just do this.
>> Override.
>> Override tape
for a player. You talking about for this
like the combine these override tape?
Never. I don't think um
I don't know what would override that.
Um
I think the tape is always going to
speak louder than anything else and if
the tape doesn't speak then it doesn't
matter anything else really. You know
that's probably the best way to say it.
>> You mentioned uh you know your defensive
staff changes stuff you guys want to do
as a coaching staff. What on that side
of the ball would you like to see more
out of players or some changes you guys
might make this season? Well, I think
there's a number of things we'll tell
the players when we come in some things
that we can clean up and I think uh more
importantly, man, now that we've it's
for the most part it's the same system,
but man, we evolved last year and doing
a lot more thing trying to create a lot
more looks to the opponent. Uh create
more headaches. Um was it perfect? Of
course it wasn't perfect, but God,
there's so much room to grow. So, I
think it's more about the players now.
Um you know, who is the most
instinctual? who's who has the highest
intellect uh when it comes to defensive
football uh with where we're at Detroit
Lions. Well, figure out who that is and
get to their level. Like, how do we get
to the next level all of our guys? And I
think that's really what it's about is
man, we're we're out of this this first
second level and we get to 401. Uh if we
can do that and add a couple of things,
tweak a few things, I just I'd love
where we could go with this. Um so, I
think that's the big thing.
Yeah, I do. I I think it that's going to
be important for us what you know,
however we go about that and it's easier
said than done. Um, you know, you only
have so many resources to be able to do
it. But I do think it's important, you
know, if you can't if you can't say, and
I'm not saying we would or we wouldn't,
but if you can't say, uh, for sure, I
know without any question, without any
doubt, the player that we're going to
acquire or that we sign is a starter,
then he better be able to shake it up.
You know what I mean? He better be able
to, well, we know this. He's going to go
in there and create a lot of uh chaos in
a good way. healthy chaos, healthy
competition, and uh and make sure that
those guys are constantly uh you know,
somebody's always dangling the carrot
and uh because I just think that there
again, it lifts the floor, man. And if
it lifts the floor, it makes your whole
team better.
Yeah, I think it there's always that
that balancing act between and when I
think of splash, you know, you're saying
uh name recognition, right? Uh so I
don't think of it like that, but I think
if it aligns to where the splash, the
money, and the player all meet because
it's worthy of that on the tape, then
absolutely. Um but then if you do that
you're out everything else. So the
competition, the the depth, the you know
the quality depth or you know that would
suffer. Um so is it worth it? You know
and that that's the juggling act that
that Brad and I constantly go through
you know and uh and we think through and
what is right and what should we do?
What can we do? Um do we have the
resources? So all of those conversations
we've had we continue to have. Um, and
they're all good, you know, cuz they
make you go through all this whole
process of figuring out what's the best
way to get our our team a little bit
better, man. And uh, and get over the
hump.
>> Thank you, guys.
>> Say it again.
>> David
>> getting in Washington.
>> Oh, god. Yeah. I thought you were like,
you didn't
>> No, it's not you. It's not you. Uh, I
love Blau. I mean, we we he was one of
the guys that I wanted to bring in and
and uh you know, Coach Quinn and those
guys went ahead and named him OC, which
is smart by them. I I think uh Blau is a
young rising coach in this league. Um
I've been around him firsthand and uh
he's another one, man. He's sharp. You
know, he understands football and
quarterback play. He knows the run game.
Um and and he's a detailed guy and he's
competitive, man. He's very competitive.
So, I think he's going to do a great
job. Thank you, guys. Yep. Thanks,
>> [music]